THAO NGUYEN

W https://thaotn.me

E thao_nguyen@alumni.brown.edu

P 650.417.1018

Multidisciplinary UX and visual designer with experience in visual brand identity, UX research and design, illustration, graphic design, creative coding, and interactive prototyping.

Quick learner who loves impactful, empathetic user-facing work and is interested in social good and helping underserved communities.

EXPERIENCE

GOOGLE · NYC

UX/Visual Designer | Jan 2019 - Present

Manages full UX research and design for a product, including analytics, user interviews, validation testing, prototyping, and development.

Created complete brand system, including logo, visual system, assets, and animations.

TIME INC · NYC

Web Designer/Developer | Aug 2017 - Jan 2019

Designed custom components for InStyle, People, EW, and Fortune, such as Fall TV Calendar and timelines for continuing news events.

SQUARE INC · SF

UX Engineer | Dec 2016 - June 2017

Managed full UX research and design for an internal product dealing with complex financial data, including iteration, testing, prototyping, and development.

EDUCATION

BROWN UNIVERSITY · PROVIDENCE, RI

BS Applied Math | Sept 2012 - May 2016

Computer Science, Web Applications, UI/UX, Software Engineering, Psychology, HCI

SCHOOL OF VISUAL ARTS - NYC

Continuing Education

Designing Brand Identity, Illustration, Graphic Design, UX Design, Typography, Form & Color

COMMUNITY OUTREACH

LGBT ASYLUM PROJECT · SF

Visual Designer | Feb 2021 - June 2021

Designed 2021 annual report, containing infographics, illustration spreads, and also refined the organization's visual system and guidelines...

SYLVIA RIVERA LAW PROJECT · NYC

UX Designer | Jan 2019 - Feb 2019

Designed workflow for incarcerated LGBTQ immigrants to receive legal help or contact legal assistance.

DSA · NYC

Lead UX Designer | Jan 2019 - Present

Designed marketing website, news site, and monthly event calendar to help activists organize.

SKILLS

Sketch, Figma, InVision, and other design/prototyping tools Adobe CS (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, After Effects) React Native, Typescript, HTML5/CSS3, Java, Python